Guide to the Henry Ernest Sigerist Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Professional Activities, 1920-1957, 1978; Series II; 3 linear feet (7 boxes)
  - Research and Writing
    - "Das Bild des Menschen in der Modernen Medizin," Neue Blätter: typescript carbon, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 60)
    - Notebooks with observations on medical care in the Soviet Union, 1938 (Box 34, Folder 61)
    - Miscellaneous articles: tear sheets, 1939-1957 (Box 35, Folder 62)
    - "War and Culture," Bulletin of the History of Medicine: manuscript, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 63)
    - Bulletin of the History of Medicine: typescripts of news from Europe, 1947-1948 (Box 35, Folder 64)
    - Bibliography of Richard Koch: notes, typescript, [1949?] (Box 35, Folder 65)
    - Review of viola concert performed by Jascha Veissi: manuscript, typescript, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 66)
    - Medicine and Human Welfare: orders and royalty statements, 1951 (Box 35, Folder 67)
    - "Auf dem Weg zur Sozialen Medizin," Die Neue Weltschau: typescript, 1953 (Box 35, Folder 68)
    - Introduction to Paul Röthlisberger, ed., "Breviarum Medicorum": drafts, 1953-1954 (Box 35, Folder 69)
    - "The Latin Medical Literature of the Early Middle Ages," Journal of the History of Medicine: manuscript and typescript footnotes, posthumously edited galley proofs, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 70)
    - Reviews and advertisements of Sigerist's books, 1958-1967 (Box 35, Folder 71)
    - On the History of Medicine: typescripts of certain chapters, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 72)
    - "An Introduction of the. Economics of Medicine," On the Sociology of Medicine: transcription of 1941 manuscript, letters by Leslie Falk, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 73)
    - "Report on India," On the Sociology of Medicine: manuscript, two typescripts, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 74)
    - On the Sociology of Medicine: typescripts of certain chapters, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 75)
    - A History of Medicine, Volume II, Preface: typescript carbon, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 76)
    - A History of Medicine, Volume II: "Original (old version)" typescript, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 77)
    - Autobiographical Writings: clippings and edited typescript carbon, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 78)
    - A. Bibliography of the Writings of Henry E. Sigerist: photocopy of typescript, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 79)
    - Arthur J. Viseltear, "The George Rosen-Henry E. Sigerist Correspondence,": offprint, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 80)
    - "Culture and Disease": typescript for reprint from Kyklos, 1928, undated (Box 36, Folder 81)
    - "History of Dietetics": typescript, undated (Box 36, Folder 82)
    - "Unpublished preface to a book on Jewish medicine": manuscript notes, typescript, undated (Box 36, Folder 83)
  - Universities
    - University of Zurich
      - Zurich (canton), Department of Education: correspondence re: certification, 1920-1924 (Box 36, Folder 84)
      - Invitation to Sigerist's inaugural lecture, 1921 (Box 36, Folder 85)
      - Financial records, 1921-1925 (Box 36, Folder 86)
      - Medical Faculty: letters from the Dean, 1922-1923 (Box 36, Folder 86)
      - Centennial booklet, 1933 (Box 36, Folder 87)
    - University of Leipzig
      - Medical Faculty: programs and correspondence, 1927-1932, undated (Box 36, Folder 88)
      - Institute for the History of Medicine: reviews of Theodor Brugsch et al., Grundlagen and Ziele der Medizin der Gegenwar, 1928-1931 (Box 36, Folder 89)
      - Institute for the History of Medicine: reviews of L. Ebermayer et al., Der Arzt and der Staat, 1929-1930 (Box 36, Folder 90)
      - Institute for the History of Medicine: reviews of Henry E. Sigerist, ed., Kyklos, Band I-IV, 1929-1932 (Box 36, Folder 91)
      - Institute for the History of Medicine: reviews of J. Wach et al., Das Problem der Kultur and die Ärztliche Psychologie, 1932 (Box 36, Folder 92)
      - Institute for the History of Medicine: reviews of miscellaneous publications, 1933, undated (Box 36, Folder 93)
      - Institute for the History of Medicine: brochures, reprints, announcement of Sigerist's lecture on American medicine, 1927-1932, undated (Box 36, Folder 94)
      - Institute for the History of Medicine: reviews of J. D. Achelis et al., Philosophische Grenzfragen der Medizin, 1930-1931 (Box 36, Folder 95)
      - Institute for the History of Medicine: "Denkschrift über die Erhaltung und den Ausbau des Instituts...", 1930 (Box 36, Folder 96)
      - Institute for the History of Medicine: records re: staff, students, and program, 1928-1931 (Box 36, Folder 97)
      - Saxony, Ministry of Education: correspondence, 1925-1928 (Box 36, Folder 98-99)
      - Saxony, Ministry of Education: correspondence and notes, 1930-1932 (Box 36, Folder 100)
    - Johns Hopkins University
      - School of Medicine: announcements of lectures and exhibitions, 1931-1934 (Box 37, Folder 101)
      - Form letters and printed matter, 1931-1936 (Box 37, Folder 102)
      - Miscellaneous papers re: curriculum and staff, 1932, undated (Box 37, Folder 103)
      - Institute for the History of Medicine: invitations, programs, 1931-1941, undated (Box 37, Folder 104)
      - Medical History Club: miscellaneous printed matter, 1938-1942 (Box 37, Folder 105)
        General note
        See also: box 41, folder 52-53
      - Graduate Week in Medical History: letters, printed matter, 1938-1942 (Box 37, Folder 106)
        See also: box 41, folder 50-51
      - Form letters and printed matter, 1948-1955 (Box 37, Folder 107)
    - Yale University
      - Correspondence, 1948-1956 (Box 37, Folder 108)
- Biographical Data and Memorabilia, 1910-1974; Series III; 3.5 linear feet (6 boxes)
  BIOGRAPHICAL DATA AND MEMORABILIA is in chronological order except that photographs (also in chronological order), oversize items, and an address file are boxed at the end of the series.
  - Zurich, Cantonal Gymnasium: humor magazine, 1910 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Scholastic records and certificates, 1910-1917 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Deed for purchase of land in Hottingen, Zurich, Switzerland, 1918 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Taschenbuch für Militärärzte, 1921-1922 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Articles about Sigerist and the Institute for the History of Medicine at Leipzig, 1922-1928 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Bibliography and autobiographical sketches, [1924-1925?] (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - "Diagnosis Concurrentialis: oder, Was meinen Sie dazu, Herr Kollege? Ein Nachtspuk": satirical play, 1926 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Facsimile of a sixteenth-century Strasburg translation of "Fasciculus medicinae eines Johannes de Ketham", 1927 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Datebook, 1932 October 10-December 31 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Rotary International: miscellaneous printed matter, 1932 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Theater and concert programs, 1931-1934 (Box 38, Folder 11-18)
  - Printed matter from travels, 1931-1934, undated (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Printed matter, hotel bills, and miscellaneous papers re: travels, 1932-1934, undated (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Articles about Sigerist, 1932-1934, undated (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Lists and schedules: "Daily Schedule," "Opera Minora," "Books," "Five-Year Plan, 1923-1937," "Second Five-Year Plan," "Lecture Engagements, 1933-1934", 1932-1934, undated (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Salt House Press: brochures, 1933 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Baltimore City Health Department: correspondence and press release re: Sigerist's radio broadcast on "The Plague", 1933 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Roland Park Country School: brochures and miscellaneous papers, 1934, undated (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Articles about Sigerist, 1939-1947, undated (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Théâtre des Champs-Elysées, [1942] (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - Parody of a letter to the editor of the Baltimore Evening Sun, [1942-1945] (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - "Vita and Bibliography of Henry E. Sigerist": carbon of typescript prepared by friends to support his nomination for the Lenin Peace Prize, [1945-1946] (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Farewell dinner: mailing list and related papers, 1947 (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - List of memberships in professional societies, [1947?] (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - Historical conferences at Pura: programs, 1950-1967 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Articles in honor of Sigerist's sixtieth birthday, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 33)
    See also: Box 42, folder 62
  - "Extract from 'American Foundations and their Fields'" re: the Bollingen Foundation, [1955-1957?] (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - Henry E. Sigerist Research Fund: leaflet, 1956 (Box 40, Folder 35)
  - Obituaries, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 36)
  - Henry E, Sigerist Research Fund Committee: minutes and circulars, 1957-1963 (Box 40, Folder 37)
  - Articles about Sigerist, 1958-1974 (Box 40, Folder 38)
  - Etchings for bookplate, "Ex Libris Sigerist Escher", undated (Box 40, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1922-1956, undated (Box 40, Folder 40)
  - Photographs
    - Henry Sigerist, [1910s-1920s] (Box 40, Folder 41)
    - Henry Sigerist at the Institute for the History of Medicine, Leipzig, [1925-1932] (Box 40, Folder 42)
    - Henry Sigerist and others, [1920s-1932?] (Box 40, Folder 43)
    - Karl Sudhoff alone and in groups, [1920s-1930s?] (Box 40, Folder 44)
    - Henry Sigerist departing from Leipzig, [1932] (Box 40, Folder 45)
    - Henry Sigerist and others, 1932-1933, [1930s] (Box 41, Folder 46)
    - Henry Sigerist and [William H. Welch?] at the annual meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1933 (Box 41, Folder 47)
    - Johns Hopkins University, Institute for the History of Medicine: staff, [1934] (Box 41, Folder 48)
    - "Claude Bernard Exhibit", 1938 (Box 41, Folder 49)
    - Johns Hopkins University, Graduate Week in Medical History
      - Concert, 1938 (Box 41, Folder 50)
      - Gathering, 1939 (Box 41, Folder 51)
    - Johns Hopkins University, Medical History Club
      - Gathering, [1930s] (Box 41, Folder 52)
      - Theatrical production, [1930s] (Box 41, Folder 53)
    - Johns Hopkins University, William H. Welch Medical Library: floor plans, [1930s] (Box 41, Folder 54)
    - Johns Hopkins University: medical buildings, [1930s?] (Box 41, Folder 55)
    - Henry Sigerist in his office at the Institute for the History of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University, [1930s] (Box 41, Folder 56)
    - Henry Sigerist, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 57)
    - Henry Sigerist and others at Pura, [1947-1950] (Box 41, Folder 58)
    - Henry Sigerist, 1949 (Box 41, Folder 59)
  - Oversize
    - Student certificates, 1910-1914 (Box 42, Folder 60)
    - Photographs of Sigerist, [1920s-1930s] (Box 42, Folder 61)
    - Articles in honor of Sigerist's sixtieth birthday, 1951 (Box 42, Folder 62)
  - Address file, undated (Box 43, Folder 63)
- Additional Material, 1931-(1944-1952)-1960; Accession 1981-M-006; 7 linear feet (12 boxes)
  This addition to the Henry E. Sigerist Papers was received from the Yale Medical Historical Library in January 1981. The papers were. collected by Sigerist's friend and supporter, John Farquhar Fulton, who was Sterling Professor of Physiology and of the History of Medicine at Yale. They include an extensive run of correspondence between Fulton and Sigerist, Fulton's correspondence with others concerning Sigerist, drafts and reprints of Sigerist's writings, and miscellaneous personal material regarding Sigerist.
  The papers are arranged in three sections: Correspondence, Writings, and Biographical Data and Memorabilia. Correspondence is divided into two subsections, General and Topical. The General Correspondence consists almost entirely of correspondence between Fulton and Sigerist, and it contains a number of exchanges which are not included in the main body of the Sigerist papers. The Topical Correspondence includes material on Sigerist's appointment in Yale University and on Fulton's efforts to obtain financial support for Sigerist's research. Writings includes manuscript drafts of volumes one and two of Sigerist's A History of Medicine. The Oversize box contains a photograph of a farewell dinner, the Sudhoff Medal, and a film of Sigerist at Pura.
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - Cushing, Harvey, 1931-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Fulton, John Farquhar, 1930-1950 October-Nov, 1952-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2-7)
    - Topical
      - Terry Lectures, Yale University: correspondence and clippings, 1938 November (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Johns Hopkins University re: resignation and move to Switzerland, 1944 April-1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Appointment in Yale University
        - Correspondence, 1944 April-1947 May, 1947 January-1949, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
        - Correspondence: J. F. Fulton and treasurer's office, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Sigerist farewell dinner
        - Correspondence: J. F. Fulton and Stuart Mudd, 1947 February-March (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - Correspondence, 1947 February-April (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - Correspondence: J. F. Fulton and Iago Galdston, 1947 February-May (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - Correspondence: J. F. Fulton and Henry Schuman, 1947 February-May (Box 2, Folder 17)
        - Correspondence: J.F. Fulton and Lottie Gordon, 1947 February-June (Box 2, Folder 18)
        - Correspondence: J.F. Fulton and Genevieve Miller, 1947 February-1948 January (Box 2, Folder 19)
        - Invitations and responses (sponsors)
          - Ackerknecht-Gregg, 1947 March (Box 2, Folder 20)
          - Guerlac-Pogo, 1947 March (Box 2, Folder 21)
          - Proskauer-Zilboorg, and "regrets", 1947 March (Box 2, Folder 22)
        - Correspondence: J.F. Fulton and George Rosen, 1947 March-April (Box 2, Folder 23)
        - Correspondence: J.F. Fulton and Richard Shryock, 1947 March-May (Box 2, Folder 24)
        - Correspondence re: dinner speakers, 1947 March-May (Box 2, Folder 25)
        - Guest "regrets" with donations, 1947 April (Box 2, Folder 26)
        - Invitations and regrets (guests), 1947 April (Box 2, Folder 27)
        - Correspondence re: dinner speakers, 1947 April-May (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - Correspondence and speech text Gregory Zilboorg, 1947 April-May (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - Correspondence.: J.F. Fulton and Robert Leslie, 1947 April-1948 May (Box 2, Folder 30)
        - Printed invitation, program and photographs, 1947 May 9 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        - Correspondence and speech texts: J.F. Fulton, 1947 May-September (Box 2, Folder 32)
        - Correspondence, agendas and lists, 1947, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
        - Bulletin of the History of Medicine, "Henry E. Sigerist Valedictory Number": journal, 1948 January-February
          See: box 12, Folder 2
      - Correspondence: J. F. Fulton and concerned friends re: Sigerist's finances, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Whitney (Helen Hay) Foundation and Whitney, John Hay: correspondence re: support for Sigerist, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Rockefeller Foundation: correspondence re: support for Sigerist, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Sale of Haller Books: J.F. Fulton, 1955 November-1956 July (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Writings
    - "An English Translation of Sandstrom's Glandulae Parathryeoideae," Bulletin of the History of Medicine: correspondence, 1936 December-1938 March (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Civilization and Disease
      - Manuscript draft, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 40-44)
    - "The University's Dilemna": manuscript draft, 1943 June-July (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - "The History of Science in Postwar Education": manuscript draft and reprint, [1943?] August 21-September (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - "Twenty-five Years of Health Work in the Soviet Union": manuscript draft and reprint, 1943 September 4 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - "Medical Care Through Medical Centers in the Soviet Union" manuscript draft and reprint, 1943 December 3 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Bulletin of the History of Medicine: reprints, 1943-1946 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - "The Study of Medicine in Wartime": manuscript draft and reprint, 1944 January 2 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - "Rural Health Services in the Soviet Union": manuscript draft and reprint, 1944 February 1 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Reprints, 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - A History of Medicine, Volume I
      - Manuscript draft, 1945 July-October (Box 4, Folder 53-54)
      - Manuscript draft, 1945-1946 January-Jun, 1946 July-1947 Nov, 1948 January-April (Box 5, Folder 55-59)
      - Manuscript draft, 1948 June-Sep, 1948 Nov, circa 1948 (Box 6, Folder 60-64)
      - Manuscript draft, Circa 1948. (Box 7, Folder 65-66)
      - Typescript draft, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 67-69)
      - Typescript draft, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 70-72)
      - Reviews, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - "The Study of the History of Medicine in Russia," translated from Russian: manuscript draft, 1947 August 20 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Book Reviews
      - Manuscript draft, 1947-1949, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 75-76)
      - Manuscript draft, 1949-1950, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 77-78)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Manuscript draft, 1947-1948, circa 1948-1954, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 79-82)
    - A History of Medicine, Volume II (Box 9, Folder 79-82)
    - Manuscript draft, 1949 July- 1950 Mar, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 83-85)
    - Manuscript draft, 1952, circa 1952 (Box 10, Folder 86-89)
    - Letters: manuscript draft, 1950-1955 (Box 10, Folder 90)
    - "Thoughts on the Physician's Writing and Reading," International Record of Medicine, 1955 October (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - History of American Medicine: typescript, 1957 February 27 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Biographical Data and Memorabilia
    - Photographs: Henry Sigerist and others, Circa 1920-1957 (Box 11, Folder 93-94)
    - Reviews, clippings, tear sheets and other biographical material, 1931- 1966 (Box 11, Folder 95)
    - America's Future: newspaper, 1938 November (Box 11, Folder 96)
    - Gesnerus, Vierteljahrschrift, herausgegeben vonder Schweizerischen Gessellschaft fur Geschichteder Medizin und der Naturwissenschaften, Festschrift zum 60 Geburtstag von Henry E. Sigerist: journal, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 97)
    - Obituaries, memorials and correspondence, 1957 March- May (Box 11, Folder 98)
    - Obituaries and memorials, 1957 June- Nov, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 99-100)
    - Obituaries and memorials, 1960
      See: box 12 folders 1-3
  - Oversize
    - Sudhoff Medal, 1933 November 26 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Photograph of farewell dinner, 1947 May 9 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Film of Sigerist at Pura, 1951 July 29 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Die Schweizerische Naturforschende Gesellschaft - Ordentlicher Mitglied, 12 September 1917 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Das Schweiz. Militärdepartement - Lieutenant der Sanitätstruppen, 3 November 1917 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Das Schweiz. Militärdepartement - oberlieutenant der Sanitätstrunpen, Arzt, 31 December 1919 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Die Antiquarische Gesellschaft in Zurich - Ordent-licher Mitglied, 6 November 1920 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Internationalis Scientiarum Historiae Comitatus - Socius Ordinarius, 17 August 1928 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Deutsche Gesellschaft für Geschichte der Medizin, Naturwissenschaft and Technik - Sudhoff-Medaille, 26 November 1933 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Delta Omega - member of A1pha Chapter, 24 April 1939 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Ateneo de Historia de la Medicina; Buenos Aires - Miembro de Honor, 1 January 1941 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Academia de Stiinte din Romania" Ehrenmitglied, 4 June 1941 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - La Sociedad de Geografia e Historia - Miembro Correspondiente, 1 August 1942 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Naturforschende Gesellschaft in Zürich - zu ihrem korrespondierenden Mitgliede, 7 September 1946 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - American Association of the History of Medicine - award of the William H. Welch Medal [Library has medal], 22 May 1950 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Societas Israelica Historiae Medicinae et Scientiarum - Socium Honorarium, 3 May 1951 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Foreign Honorary Member, 9 May 1951 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Deutsche Vereinigung für Geschichte der Medizin, Naturwissenschaft and Technik E.V. - Ehrenmitglied, 20 September 1952 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - History of Medicine Society of Tulane University Honorary Member, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, Accession 1987-M-086
  - Biographical Data and Memorabilia
    - Diary, 1933-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
    - Diary, 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 5-8)
    - Diary, 1941-1944 (Box 3, Folder 9-12)
    - Diary, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - Diary
      - Volume 1, 1947 January 1-February 17 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Volume 2, 1947 February 18-April 12 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Volume 3, 1947 April 13-June 27 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Volume 4, 1947 June 29-September 7 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Volume 5, 1947 September 8-November 12 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Volume 6, 1947 November 13-December 31 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Volume 1, 1948 January 1-March 19 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Volume 2, 1948 March 19-May 11 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Volume 3, 1948 May 11-August 15 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Volume 4, 1948 August 16-November 19 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Volume 5, 1948 November 20-December 31 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Volume 1, 1949 January 1-March 31 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Volume 2, 1949 April 1-July 9 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Volume 3, 1949 July 12-December 8 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Volume 4, 1949 December 9-December 31 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Volume 1, 1950 January 1-April 17 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Volume 2, 1950 May 8-November 10 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Volume 3, 1950 November 10-December 31 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Volume 1, 1951 January 1-December 31 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Volume 1, 1952 January 1-September 11 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Volume 2, 1952 September 12-December 31 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Volume 1, 1953 January 1-July 10 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Volume 2, 1953 July 11-October 22 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Volume 3, 1953 December 29-1954 June 19 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Volume 4, 1954 June 20 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Additional Material, 1953, 1954, undated; Accession 1991-M-085
  See Accession 1987-M-086, box 6, folder 28
  - Correspondence and reviews of Grosse, 1953 December (Box 6, Folder 28)
    Received from: Transferred from the Medical Historical Library, 1991 May 13
  - Arzte, 1954 January-Apr, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Additional Material, 1948-1954; Accession 1996-M-112
  This addition to the papers is composed of ten albums containing photographs, correspondence, concert and theater programs, postcards, and other memorabilia. These materials, which are arranged in chronological order, document Sigerist's years at Casa Serena in Pura, Switzerland. The albums include materials from numerous family events, travels, and visits with friends and colleagues. Sigerist mounted materials for the albums and wrote captions on each page.
  - Book 1, 1950 January 1-October 8 (Box 1)
  - Book 2, 1950 October 11-1951 June 14 (Box 2)
  - Book 3, 1951 June 14-December 31 (Box 3)
  - Book 4, 1952 January 1-June 14 [appendix includes a section "Reminiscences," 1948-1951] (Box 4)
  - Book 5, 1952 June 15-December 2 (Box 5)
  - Book 6, 1952 December 2-1953 May 17 (Box 6)
  - Book 7, 1953 May 17-September 18 (Box 7)
  - Book 8, 1953 September 22-December 31 (Box 8)
  - Book 9, 1954 January 1-May 27 (Box 9)
  - Book 10, 1954 May 28-September 14 (Box 10)
- Additional Material, 1891-1991; Accession 1997-M-042
  - Calendar of long hand letters, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings
    - General, 1911-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 60th birthday, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1891-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diary
    - Tagebuch des Instituts from Leipzig, 1926-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American tour
      - pp. 1-189, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - pp. 191-250, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Memorabilia
    - Programs, 1923-1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Scholastic records and certificates, 1890s-1911 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Plans of work